There's a new buzzword that's going
around the idea of context engineering
instead of prompt engineering. We take
that very seriously and that's why also
I think search and AI are two really
important things to put together and to
think about in harmony with each other
and we discuss things internally is is
this search or is this AI and point I
usually bring is does it matter? It's
all one thing at this point, but we need
to think really seriously about not just
what we do with the LLM, but taking care
on what we bring into the LLM to get
that kind of response and accuracy.
[Music]
It's really interesting because for me
as a user, I don't necessarily care
whether it's search or AI so long as I
have that trust and confidence that in
the results that come back from a from
you as as as you know one of the folks
who who are kind of like building these
types of capabilities in in with search
and AI where would you say the
boundaries are for where where where
search has you know a real ceiling that
it can't kind of like break through but
but where AI really benefits and and and
can can deliver much better results and
and what are the problems the other way
where search is actually far stronger or
far better at being able to deliver
results where AI just struggles.
>> Yeah. So um the first part so where
where does search kind of hit its limits
and where does AI kind of um shine?
You're making me think about one of our
customers that is a major um newspaper
publication. Uh, and one of the things
that they've done which I'm just think
is so clever is right they have they
they hook into the Associated Press's
wire service right so they get you know
these pushes it's essentially an RSS
feed of every new you know headline with
a hundred words on what's going on so
that they can help orient their
journalists to what's you know keeping a
pulse on what's what is happening uh in
the world. Um, now if you think about
that as a search problem, so now I have
this channel that has all of these push
updates and then I search for something
like um, you know, what's going on in
Bulgaria, I'm just going to see tons of
text and I have to read all of those
things and it can get kind of tedious.
And especially if you think about search
where we're trying to focus on relevance
rather than trying to give you like um
the right longitudinal kind of uh
organization, it's really useful to
instead use something like our AI search
answers product which actually
synthesizes all of that information,
takes those raw search results and
translates that into um an actual kind
of human understandable text block with
citations um so that you can go back to
the relevant messages but you
better get just a sense of like what
what is actually happening. I don't have
to kind of provide that synthesis for
myself. Now on the opposite side where
where AI is limited and where search um
continues to be kind of more important
is right um there it depends on job
roles but one thing that we see a lot is
there are certain job roles where you
need to respond to every message that's
coming in and you need to understand
what what what is happening. Um, and so
that's where things like structuring
search results based on time, uh, is a
really useful use case. And so what
we've heard from users is, you know, the
need to save searches and kind of go
back to the same search as a way to
essentially triage where an LLM would
that synthesis is not what they're
looking for. What they're looking for is
every single thing. Coverage or recall
is more important. Um, so that's I think
part of the way that we're thinking
about that balance.
>> Yeah. And it's interesting you were
talking a little bit there about almost
like the combination of the two a little
bit. And and it's very interesting even
even through kind of like a bunch of dev
tools that that that uh almost like need
a level of creativity versus a level of
accuracy uh where we see certain dev
tools that that use AI as well as
looking at an AI an A or something like
that to provide them that accuracy of
what a code flow is doing and then and
then layer AI on top. And it's
interesting that uh you know is there
this is there this path where actually
one or the other isn't actually the
solution but we need this mix where
search is good at certain things AI is
good at other things. Let's actually
combine them to actually get the best of
both.
>> I mean that's what we're we're really
focused on in general is trying to use
the the both pieces of technology. Um so
an example of a feature that we just
launched that I'm particularly proud of
is something called AI explain. You can
now go to individual messages and
there's a message action you can press
that will explain the message in detail.
So I use this personally whenever I'm
responding to incidents, right? I'm a VP
of engineering. I get, you know,
mentioned in an incident channel when
something's going on and I have to
quickly get up to speed. The engineers
are still actively working the problem
and I don't want to slow them down. So
someone sends a message with a bunch of
acronyms. Maybe I don't know those
acronyms. What I would do in the past is
I'd have to ask someone. I'd either be
slowing down the people who are really
doing it or I'd have to bring more
people in. But now I can just use AI
explain to catch up with what their
communication is about so I can
understand what their acronyms are. I
can understand the details of why it's
significant without inter without
interrupting anybody. And that gives me
a much better uh ability as an executive
especially to to just get a pulse on
what's going on without having to
interrupt anybody. Um, so that is both a
search and an AI problem where we, you
know, kick off a search to get more
information and more context, but then
we're using the LM to kind of create
that synthesis as well as bring in that
kind of global knowledge of just the
context that the LM already knows and
has and and use that as part of the um
solution.
>> Really interesting. We're going to go on
and talk a little bit about how uh you
know the folks at Slack are using AI
internally as well.